reeds.com 2019-08-27

# REEDS Jewelers Privacy Policy | REEDS Jewelers

**Last updated on: August 5, 2019**

Your privacy is important to us. As your trusted jeweler since 1946, REEDS Jewelers’ focus is on providing excellence in jewelry, watches and service. We take your trust seriously and are respectful of the personal information you share with us. We make significant efforts towards ensuring the privacy and security of your personal information, as further described in this policy.

REEDS Jewelers, Inc. and our brands which include but are not limited to stores operating under the name REEDS Jewelers and other websites and stores owned and operated by REEDS Jewelers Inc. (collectively "REEDS Jewelers"), offer customer-friendly policies designed to provide a secure and safe shopping experience. The websites owned and operated by REEDS Jewelers include but are not limited to REEDS.com (collectively the "Sites").

## Our Privacy Policy addresses the following questions:

### Who is REEDS Jewelers?

Founded in 1946, REEDS Jewelers is a leading full-service multi-channel jewelry retailer, with stores in multiple states, a national direct mail catalog, and an ecommerce web site, www.Reeds.com, serving customers across all 50 states and those stationed abroad at APO/FPO addresses. To view our current roster of REEDS Jewelers store locations, please visit our [ Store Locator](https://www.reeds.com/reeds-locations.html).

For the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), the Data Controller is REEDS Jewelers, Inc. registered in North Carolina with a registered address at PO Box 2229, Wilmington, NC 28402.

_PLEASE NOTE: REEDS Jewelers is not associated with any other jewelry chain or store using the name Reeds or Reeds Jewelers._

### What Personal Information Does REEDS Jewelers Collect?

REEDS Jewelers collects Personal Information you provide to us to serve your needs. 

**“Personal Information”** , is any information that enables us to identify you, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as your name (first and last), address (city, state, ZIP), email address, telephone number, identification number, location data, or online identifier. 

Some examples of points of contact where your Personal Information may be collected include:

  * Registering for “My Account”, Wish List or Product Review account on our website;
  * Requesting that merchandise be sent to you or others, making purchases or returns with us, placing an order with us online, via phone, mail, email or fax, or requesting an e-receipt; 
  * Fulfilling orders you place and delivering packages;
  * Requesting a catalog or other content and communications from us;
  * Subscribing to REEDS.com or other REEDS Jewelers owned or operated websites, email or other communications from us or managing your preferences with us;
  * Applying for an account with us at one of our brand locations or online;
  * Providing your Financial Account numbers when transacting with us;
  * Interacting with our websites or mobile sites, mobile applications and services;
  * Electing to participate in any of our programs such as contests, sweepstakes, surveys, loyalty programs, etc.;
  * Applying for employment which may include your social security number or social insurance number;
  * Working with our sales associates who assist you with your shopping experience and purchases;
  * Communications with REEDS Jewelers;
  * Submitting request for repair;
  * Submitting request for Insurance Replacement information.

REEDS Jewelers also receives information about you from other companies, including, but not limited to information on your creditworthiness for private label credit card offers and products you may be interested in purchasing. Additionally, we may also collect Personal Information about you from other third parties, such as demographic firms, to make our future service and marketing efforts more efficient and personalized for you. We generally do not receive information about EU citizens or residents from other companies; for these persons we will notify you when we receive Personal Information about you from them and the purposes for which we intend to use that information. 

We may combine all information we collect and we may disclose this information within our corporate family of companies or our service providers. 

When you visit our Sites we may also gather certain Personal Information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or other device identifiers, browser information, Internet Service Provider (ISP), operating system, location, date/time stamp and clickstream data.

REEDS Jewelers is a highly ethical company and requires the highest standard of conduct from our employees and business partners. We are a member of the Better Business Bureau, Jewelers of America, Gemological Institute of America, Jewelers Vigilance Committee, and other distinguished industry organizations; we strive to adhere to the Direct Marketing Association's Guidelines for Ethical Business Practice, Shopping and Consumer Rights and the DMA's Privacy Promise.

### How Does REEDS Jewelers Use The Personal Information Collected?

REEDS Jewelers may use the information collected as follows:

  * to complete your purchase transactions and provide the services you request;
  * to send you catalogs and other offerings through the mail;
  * to contact you about the status of your orders;
  * to identify your product and service preferences, so that you can be informed of new or additional products, services, and promotions that might be of interest to you;
  * to notify you of product recalls or provide other information concerning products you have purchased;
  * to process and respond to your application for current or future career opportunities;
  * to process membership requests when you apply or otherwise administer your participation in our programs;
  * to respond to your comments, questions or complaints, determine your satisfaction with our programs and service, to personalize your experiences;
  * to send you marketing communications and other information you have chosen to receive regarding our products, services, marketing or special events;
  * to use your Personal Information for our everyday business purposes such as security, payment processing, analytics, operations, fraud detection and prevention, reporting, making back-ups and legal compliance;
  * to submit or process your watch repair through the watch repair center;
  * to submit or process you insurance replacement claim; and
  * to improve our merchandise selections, customer service, and overall customer shopping experience.

REEDS Jewelers may supply the third party firm with just the Personal Information necessary for this partner to deliver an offer, product or service to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices for not having this information used by third-party service providers, please visit: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Or you learn how to opt-out of 3rd party tracking by going to our section: How can I opt-out of 3rd party tracking?

### What Personal Information Does REEDS Jewelers Share with Others?

**Affiliated Partners** : REEDS Jewelers may share the collected Personal Information with affiliated partner companies and licensees in order to deliver contractually designated products and services. For example, in some cases we may use service provider partners to help us perform some of these tasks, including, but not limited to, processing or fulfilling your orders or performing customer service, business analyses or quality control (e.g., we use carriers such as UPS and FedEx to deliver packages to our customers), and consequently we may share your contact information with these service providers

In such cases, we will require these service providers to enter into agreements with us regarding the confidential handling of your Personal Information.

We may also provide your contact information to your credit card issuer or to credit card processors for their purposes in processing your order. In certain instances we may disclose your Personal Information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify you, contact you, to advise you of a product recall, detect and protect you or us from fraud, manage information security or bring legal action to protect your rights or the rights of REEDS Jewelers or others. We may also disclose your Personal Information when you ask us to do so or when we believe it is required or permitted by law.

When you make a purchase through or register with the Sites, you provide us with an email address where we, or these service providers, may contact you for the purposes described in this section. For example, you may request to receive package tracking updates from one of our service providers.

### Does REEDS Jewelers use Third-Party Advertising?

REEDS Jewelers uses third-party service providers to place Internet advertisements (banners or links) on our behalf. These advertising service providers may collect non-identifiable information about your visits to our Sites, and your interactions with our products and services. Such non-identifiable information does not include your name, address, e-mail address or other personal information. The information is collected through the use of cookies and pixel tags (also known as action tags), which are industry-standard technology used by most major websites.

In addition to the information about your visits to our website, our service providers may also use the information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements for products and services available from REEDS Jewelers.

Currently, we use third party-placed tracking pixels and cookies from the following advertising delivery partners: Google, Fetchback, SalesCycle, Criteo, Adnxs, LinkConnector, Channel Advisor, Bronto, and NetElixir. In the future we may partner with other companies to provide interest-based advertising, both on and off our Sites.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices for not having this information used by third-party service providers, please visit: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

**Legal Disclosures** : In the unlikely event REEDS Jewelers is required to disclose Personal Information pursuant to lawful requests, such as subpoenas or court orders, or in compliance with applicable laws, REEDS Jewelers will make such disclosure. In the event the ownership of all or a part of a business within REEDS Jewelers were to change, Personal Information pertinent to that business's operations would likely be transferred to, or licensed for use by, the new owner.

**Third Party Offers** : If REEDS Jewelers chooses to offer you selected third party products and services that we think would be of benefit to you and you accept the offer, REEDS Jewelers would supply this third party firm with just the Personal Information necessary for this partner to deliver the offer, product or service to you. 

**REEDS Jewelers Credit Card Account** : We may share your information with the bank that issues REEDS Jewelers credit card accounts, Synchrony Bank. (You can read their privacy policy at <https://www.synchronybank.com/privacy/>.)

### How Can I Access And Correct Information Collected?

You can update or correct your name, address, telephone number or email address for the Sites or REEDS Jewelers catalog at any time by visiting the Sites and clicking on the My Info link at the top of the page and then completing Register/Login. To view or correct any of this information, you may also contact us by mail, phone or email as further described at [How Can I Opt Out Of Receiving Further Communications From REEDS Jewelers? ](https://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html%3Ehttps://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html%3C/a%3E.%3C/p%3E%3Ch3%20id=)

#### How to be removed from the REEDS Jewelers Paper Catalog Mailing List

You can [contact us](https://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html "contact us") by mail, phone or email and simply request that you be removed from the catalog mailing list.

We will make every effort to implement any choice you make as soon as possible, but you should allow approximately three months for mailing change requests to be fully implemented due to lead times with external vendors on printed materials.

#### How to unsubscribe from the REEDS Jewelers email Marketing List 

You may click on the Unsubscribe link on any promotional emails you receive from REEDS Jewelers. You can contact us by mail, phone or email at the address or phone number above. You may also click on the Remove from email / mailing list link at the bottom of every page.

Once you have unsubscribed, you will be removed from receiving future email solicitations, apart from those that have already been processed before this request was received. Note that unsubscribing from promotional emails will not affect your receipt of order status emails which will still be provided to you after purchasing online at the Sites.

### Are REEDS Jewelers Credit Cards Available?

Yes. You can apply for a REEDS Jewelers credit card account to receive special offers and participate in exclusive brand benefits. Read more on the Apply for a Credit Card page. The REEDS Card also offers an online portal to update your personal credit card account information, view your statement and pay your credit card bill online, add authorized buyers to your account and request a credit limit increase. For more information on REEDS Jewelers credit services provided by Synchrony Bank, visit [https://www.synchronybank.com/privacy/](https://www.reeds.com/reeds-credit-card.html).

### Does REEDS Jewelers Send Unsolicited Promotional Emails?

No. REEDS Jewelers only sends marketing email offers to customers who have explicitly requested them. To request occasional promotional email offers, notifying you of special deals, web-only offers, product previews, and in-store events for stores near you, you may sign up for Email Offers on the Sites, or call, fax or write us at the address listed above. To remove your name from any email offer list, click the unsubscribe link in any of our marketing emails you receive, login to My Account under the My Info section, or contact our Customer Service Center. Registered users who have purchased from the Sites will receive standard order status communications, such as order confirmation, shipping dates, etc. via email at the registered email account the user has designated. Your choice to opt-in or opt-out of promotional emails will not affect the order status and registration service.

### How Does REEDS Jewelers Safeguard the Personal Information Collected?

REEDS Jewelers protects against unauthorized disclosures by limiting access to only those REEDS Jewelers employees who need the Personal Information to do their jobs. REEDS Jewelers employees are trained about their responsibility to protect our customers' privacy. We limit the Personal Information we provide to outside companies to only the Personal Information we believe is appropriate to enable them to carry out their responsibilities under our contracts or to offer you products and services we think might be of interest to you. We contractually require that the Personal Information provided be used only for the specifically authorized purpose and that its confidentiality be maintained.

### Is My Online Transaction Secure?

Yes. We use prevailing security technology to ensure that your shopping experience will be safe and secure. We encrypt your Personal Information, including your name, address, and credit card number when transmitting over the Internet using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) security technology. We strive to update our security procedures and enhance our Sites to meet prevailing encryption standards.

You can check for a secure connection by looking at the URL line of your browser. When accessing a secure server, the first characters of the site address will change from "http" to "https."

**PLEASE NOTE THAT NORMAL E-MAIL (such as using the[ contact us](https://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html "contact us") form on the Sites, or sending an email via your home email service) IS NOT ENCRYPTED AND THUS IS NOT A SECURE MEANS FOR TRANSMITTING CREDIT CARD INFORMATION OR ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU WISH TO KEEP PRIVATE AND SECURE.**

### Where is my Personal Information Stored?

The Personal Information we receive will be held in the computers and systems of our offices and data centers in the United States, and the offices and data centers of our service providers, and may be accessed by or given to our staff or designees working outside the United States or the European Union. 

If you are outside the United States, please note that your Personal Information may be processed by us in the United States, where laws regarding data protection may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By using our Sites and by providing any Personal Information to the Sites, all users, including without limitation users in Canada and the European Union, fully understand and expressly consent to the collection and processing of such Personal Information in the United States. 

### Does REEDS Jewelers Use Cookies?

REEDS Jewelers uses HTML cookies and web beacon technology to enhance the browsing and shopping experience on the Sites. We use cookies and web beacons to identify your device, provide website user authentication, conduct fraud prevention and management services, distinguish you from other visitors, record your IP address and understand your use of our Sites, and identify the name of the website from which you linked to REEDS Jewelers. This information is used to help us serve you better by improving our website design, as well as our products, services, and promotions, and for obligations with our business partners. Information obtained through cookies and web beacons may be shared with or obtained by service providers on our behalf. More information is available under Third-Party Advertising Partners.

Please note: While navigating on the Rolex section of our website, some cookies are controlled by ROLEX SA which applies the following [Cookies Policy](https://www.rolex.com/footer/cookies.html).

Cookies are small files or records that are place on your computer's hard drive to collect information about your activities when you visit a website. A "session cookie" expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A "persistent cookie" stores information on the hard drive so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date, the cookie information is still available. A web beacon is a small string of code that represents a clear graphic image and is used in conjunction with a cookie. When you visit our Sites, we may use both a session and a persistent cookie. This REEDS-placed cookie may contain information (such as a unique user ID) that is used to track your usage of our website and in some cases, your e-mail address. Your e-mail address is only saved in this REEDS-placed cookie if you register with us. The REEDS-placed cookie is also used for the auto-saved shopping cart so that when a user returns, the contents of their shopping cart are automatically retrieved. A web beacon allows us to capture certain additional types of information about a visitor's actions on a website, such as a visitor's cookie number, the time, date, duration and number of page views, a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed, and details about any items that were purchased. If you save your information with or order from us, we may also use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our website. If you have not saved your information with or ordered from us, we may monitor and maintain information about your use of our website in a manner that does not identify you. You can disable cookies at any time by using your browser options; however, if you turn off cookies, we may not be able to track your order or enable you to make a purchase from our website. In addition, we will not be able to recognize you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information. These cookies transmit information back to the REEDS Jewelers’ web site computers; these computers are, generally speaking, the only computers which are authorized to read such information. The information captured makes it possible for us to, for example, (i) speed navigation, keep track of items in your shopping cart, and provide you with custom tailored experiences and content; (ii) remember information you gave to us so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit REEDS Jewelers sites; (iii) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing; and (iv) use analytics to monitor the performance of our websites and services.

You can choose to have your web browser notify you every time a cookie is being sent to you or you can turn off cookie acceptance altogether. Note that if you disable cookies, your overall shopping experience may be adversely affected as certain functionality will not work without cookies. You are welcome to contact us via phone, e-mail or postal mail for shopping assistance if you do not wish to use our website.

### Does REEDS Jewelers Aggregate Information?

REEDS Jewelers has selected Google Analytics to assist us in improving our Sites. Google Analytics collects information on our Sites through first-party data collection by placing cookies on your computer. The information that is collected through these cookies is aggregated and anonymized by Google Analytics to provide information such as how people navigate through our Sites, and how to improve the overall shopping experience. Google Analytics does not collect credit card, username or password information. The information that is collected by Google Analytics is analyzed by Google Analytics and is accessed by REEDS Jewelers through a secure web connection. Google Analytics is required to maintain all information collected and its analysis in confidence. As a visitor to the Sites, you have the choice to deactivate the ability of Google Analytics to include your usage in its analytics. To learn more about Google Analytics privacy, please visit <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>.

### What is the REEDS Jewelers Policy with Respect To Data Collection From Children?

REEDS Jewelers does not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under the age of 13 on our Sites.

If we become aware that an individual is under the age of 13 and has submitted any Personal Information to REEDS Jewelers for any purpose without prior verifiable parental consent, we will delete his or her Personal Information from our files.

For more information on laws protecting children's privacy online, visit the US Federal Trade Commission's web site on the 1999 Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) at <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html>.

### What is REEDS Jewelers Mobile Privacy Policy?

REEDS Jewelers Inc. offers mobile applications (commonly known as "apps") that allow you to shop online, check product availability, learn about store events, or receive other information from REEDS Jewelers. All Personal Information collected by REEDS Jewelers via our mobile application is protected by this Privacy Policy. When you download our mobile application, you may choose to allow it to obtain your precise location from your mobile device when you click the "near me" button. In this case, we will determine your zip code from the precise location data received from your mobile device. We do not store precise location data; we only store the zip code associated with the location.

In the future, we may offer updated or enhanced versions of our mobile applications that include additional features created by us or using third party functionality. Our applications or the third party may automatically collect information about your precise location from your device, but only if you allow it.

### Does REEDS Jewelers use Social Media Plug-ins?

REEDS Jewelers invites you to socialize and share your fashion inspiration, finds and purchases with your friends using Social Media tools such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Instagram. If you choose to use these tools, you may be sharing certain profile elements, including your comments. This sharing is subject to each social media program's privacy policies. We also use Facebook Social Plugins to allow Facebook to share information and friends' activities with its members while they are on our website. For example, Social Plugins allow Facebook to show you and your friends' "Likes" on our product pages if you are logged into Facebook while shopping at REEDS.com. REEDS Jewelers does not receive or control any of the content from Facebook Social Plugins. To remove a Facebook "Like" through REEDS.com, place your cursor in the "grayed out" Like button and click on the "X" that appears. This removes the "Like" from your Facebook Page, as well as from REEDS Jewelers’ websites. You can also delete comments made while at REEDS.com from your Facebook Page.

For more information about Facebook Social Plugins and other social media tools, click here: [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins).

We may allow you to sign in to your online account using Facebook Connect or other social media interfaces. If you choose to do this, we may collect information necessary to facilitate social interactions such as friend lists, birthday, check-ins, basic profile information and your profile picture but only if the privacy settings you and your friends set within Facebook or the other social media interfaces allow it. We will use the information we collect to create and facilitate an interactive social experience and to bring you products, services and programs from REEDS Jewelers. REEDS Jewelers will always comply both with its Privacy Policy as well as with Facebook Connect terms regarding use of Facebook profile information. Google+, Twitter, Pinterest and other interfaces we actively promote.

### Is it safe to click on Links to Other Websites and Services?

The Sites may include links to other Internet sites, content, or videos (embedded or direct links) maintained by third parties (“Linked Sites”). REEDS Jewelers provides Linked Sites to you solely as a convenience, and the inclusion of Linked Sites does not imply endorsement by REEDS Jewelers. You access Linked Sites at your own risk, and by accessing them you leave our Sites. Linked Sites are not under the control of REEDS Jewelers and REEDS Jewelers is not responsible for the contents of any Linked Site, including the privacy policies or tracking technologies they may use. We encourage you to check the applicable privacy policy to determine how they will handle any personally identifying information they collect from you.

### Does REEDS Jewelers Recognize Browser Do Not Track Signals?

Our Sites typically honor Do Not Track signals for the most popular web browsers; however it is possible that a web browser or one of our service providers may make a modification, update or release which would cause this functionality to fail on our Sites. To learn more about browser tracking signals and Do Not Track, please visit <http://www.allaboutdnt.org/>.

### What Are My European Data Subject Rights?

Under EU data protection law, individuals within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) have the right to prevent REEDS Jewelers processing your Personal Information for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your Personal Information) if we intend to use your Personal Information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your Personal Information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your Personal Information. You can also exercise the right by [contacting us](https://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html "contact us") at our Customer Service Center by phone, email or postal mail.

Under European data protection law, in certain circumstances, individuals within the EEA have the right to:

  * request access to any Personal Information we hold about you (“Subject Access Request”) as well as related information, including the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the Personal Information has been shared;
  * obtain without undue delay the rectification of any inaccurate Personal Information we hold about you;
  * request Personal Information held about you to be deleted provided the Personal Information is not required by Reeds Jewelers for compliance with a legal obligation under European or Member State law or for the establishment, exercise or defense of a legal claim; 
  * under certain circumstances prevent or restrict processing of your Personal Information, except to the extent processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and
  * under certain circumstances, request transfer of Personal Information directly to a third party where this is technically feasible.

Also, where you believe that REEDS Jewelers has not complied with its obligation under this Privacy Policy or European law, you have the right to make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority, such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office. 

You can exercise any of these rights by [contacting us](https://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html "contact us") at our Customer Service Center by phone, email or postal mail.

### Whom Do I Contact If I Have Additional Questions or Concerns About This Policy?

If you have any questions or concerns about REEDS Jewelers privacy policy, please [contact us](https://www.reeds.com/contacting-reeds-jewelers.html "contact us") at our Customer Service Center by phone, email, live chat or postal mail.

For more information on privacy in general, please visit the US Federal Trade Commission's site on Privacy Initiatives at <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html> or the Electronic Privacy Information Center, <http://www.epic.org/>, a public interest research center clearinghouse for privacy issues.

### What happens to my information if REEDS is sold?

REEDS Jewelers is proud to be owned and managed by the family that founded it in 1946, and aims to continue to serve customers in this manner for generations to come. In the unlikely event that REEDS Jewelers is sold in part or in whole, any customer Personal Information owned by Reeds Jewelers may be transferred with the change of ownership.

### Will the REEDS Jewelers Privacy Policy Ever Change?

Yes. This policy may be modified from time to time. You are encouraged to review this policy on a monthly basis.

### How can I Opt-out of 3rd Party Tracking??

If you would like to learn more about third party tracking and to know your choices for opting-out of third party tracking, please review the Third-Party Advertising Partners section of this Privacy Policy. California residents who wish to learn more about their rights concerning third party tracking or marketing may review the “Shine the Light” law (CA Civil Code 1798.8), or may contact us for further information at:

REEDS  
Attn: Privacy Policy  
PO Box 2229  
Wilmington, NC 28402  

Please use the phrase “California Shine the Light Request” to help us appropriately identify your question, and include your mailing address, state of residence and email address so we can provide a response.
